Okay, so we successfully sorted this
array and or sorry, filtered this array.
Um, and we were able to find those who
had less than five villains caught, but
maybe we want to keep all of the members
in the array and we just want to find um
the people or we just want to organize
them in order of the most villains
caught. So maybe let's just try to sort
them real quick. Um, so what I'm going
to do is I'm going to call this built-in
method called dotsort. And if we save
this and we come over here, let's look
at our array. Well, 10, 18, 25, 12.
Looks like it didn't sort it. It
actually did. If you look over here, it
goes Arthur, Barry, Bruce, Carter,
Clark, Courtney, Diana, Dina. And so,
you can see it sorted them in
alphabetical order, which is not what we
want. We want to sort them in numeric
order. If you're ever trying to sort
alphabetically, that is a great way to
do it. But if you want to sort them
numerically, so maybe we want to sort on
this number, then you need to give it a
function.
And I for one can never remember the
order of this function. So I generally
look it up. So right here it says sort
to sort numbers in ascending order, you
need to write a function that takes a
and b and returns a minus b.
In descending order, you take a and b
and return b minus a.
So I say I never remember but one of the
ways that you could try to remember is
this function that you give it needs to
take an A and a B
and it needs to return A minus B or B
minus A. If you want it in ascending
order then the A goes first. If you want
it in descending order then the B goes
first. Remember A goes first in
ascending order because ascending starts
with the letter A. All right. So then
we're going to say a. But remember
Justice League isn't storing numbers,
it's storing arrays. So if we want to
sort them based on the fourth position,
then we have to say a sorry at the three
position minus B at the three position.
So that will now compare 12 to 20 and
sort them. What order is it going to
sort them in? Well, A came first. A is
means ascending. So, we should get uh
Mr. Terrific first. If we come over to
Safari, sure enough, Mr. Terrific is
first and 1 2 3 3 4 5 55 5. And you can
see that we go all the way down that
list um in ascending order. If we swap
these and said, let's compare B minus A
and we save that and we come back, we
can see that they are now in descending
order, where Batman is the most
effective, having caught 20 villains
this month. And the Flash is the second
most having caught 18 villains. And we
can see that the list goes down from
there and it has been sorted. So when
you use the sort function to sort
numbers, you give it a function that
takes in two values from your array and
then it compares them. Um if you want it
in ascending order, put the a value or
the first value first. If you want it in
descending order, put the first value
second. And that is how you sort an
array in JavaScript.